- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[Hawaiian music]
[夏威夷音乐]
*
[bubbles popping]
[气泡破裂]
- [inhales, exhales]
- [吸气，呼气]
[door opens]
- Rev your excitement engines,
[门打开]
Mr. Squidward.
[grunts]
章鱼哥先生。
[咕哝]
Do ye not know
what tomorrow is?
你不知道吗
明天是什么？
- Another monotonous day
I spend walking
- 又是单调的一天
我花步行时间
in slow motion
toward an empty horizon?
慢动作
走向空旷的地平线？
- No, that's today.
Tomorrow is Food Con!
- 不，就是今天。
明天就是美食节啦！
- Whoa! Food Con!
- 哇！食品骗局！
Wait, what's a Food Con?
等等，什么是美食节？
- Additionally,
who cares?
- 另外，
谁在乎呢？
- Mr. Squidward, Food Con is
the biggest convention
最大的会议
of food fans
in the entire ocean.
美食迷的
在整个海洋中。
The best chefs and cooks
gather together and compete
最好的厨师和厨师
for the top prize,
the golden cornucopia!
为了获得最高奖项，
金色的聚宝盆！
- Oh boy!
The Krabby Patty is
- 天啊！
蟹肉饼是
a sure bet to win
the golden corn-ocobbia!
必胜的赌注
金色的玉米棒子！
- You're darn tootin'
it is!
- 你真是太TMD了
是的！
And you two will be
me right-claw men!
你们两个将会
我右爪人！
Eh, I could use some
extra muscle, though,
呃，我可以用一些
不过，额外的肌肉
to help set up the booth.
帮助搭建展位。
Hmm.
- [grunting]
唔。
- [咕哝]
[strains, grunts]
[紧张、咕哝声]
[chews]
[咀嚼]
- Perfect.
- 完美的。
Let's hit the road!
我们上路吧！
[bubbles pop]
[气泡破裂]
As you can see gentlemen,
I have spared no expense
我不遗余力
on our
transportation.
在我们的
交通。
[all exclaim]
[所有人惊呼]
[tires screech]
[轮胎尖叫声]
- Tada!
- 田田！
- Whoo!
- Oh, what a ride!
- 呼！
- 噢，多么美妙的旅程啊！
- Oh.
- 哦。
- And I brought plenty
of free samples to sell.
- 我带了很多
免费样品出售。
- This is the best day ever!
- 这是有史以来最好的一天！
both: Road trip!
[electric guitars wail]
两人：公路旅行！
[电吉他哀嚎]
[punches]
[coughs]
[拳头]
[咳嗽]
- Mm.
- 毫米。
[bubbles pop]
[气泡破裂]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- I spy with my little eye--
- Mr. Krabs!
-我用我的小眼睛监视--
- 蟹老板！
- Yes!
- [giggles]
- 是的！
- [咯咯笑]
I spy with my little eye--
- Mr. Krabs!
我用我的小眼睛窥探——
- 蟹老板！
- Oh ho! Yes, yes!
- I spy with my little eye--
- 哦嗬！是的，是的！
-我用我的小眼睛监视--
- Mr. Krabs?
- Oh! How did you know?
- 蟹老板？
- 哦！你怎么知道的？
- Enough!
- 足够的！
Ye both are barnacles
on me brain!
你们都是藤壶
在我的脑子里！
both: Whoa look at that!
两人：哇看看那个！
- The World's
Second Biggest Lump
- 世界的
第二大肿块
is only 50 miles away,
we gotta see it!
距离仅50英里，
我们一定要看看！
both: No.
两人：没有。
- The World's Least
Exciting Sweater!
- 世界上最少的
令人兴奋的毛衣！
My parents fell in love there!
We gotta go!
我们得走了！
both: Cool toilet!
[flushing]
两人：厕所真酷！
[冲水]
both: No.
- We are not stopping
两人：没有。
- 我们不会停止
till we get to Food Con!
直到我们到达美食展！
[bubbles pop]
[气泡破裂]
- Hey!
- 嘿！
[horn blares]
[screams]
[喇叭声]
[尖叫声]
- Hey!
- 嘿！
[moans, snores]
[truck horn honks]
[呻吟声、打鼾声]
[卡车喇叭鸣响]
[babbling, growls]
[胡言乱语，咆哮]
For the last time,
we get it!
最后一次，
我们明白了！
Trucks have horns!
卡车有喇叭！
- Come on Squidward.
Give it a try!
- 来吧，章鱼哥。
尝试一下！
If I do,
will you promise to stop?
如果我这样做，
你会答应停下来吗？
both: Yes!
两人：是的！
- All right.
Hey!
- 好的。
嘿！
[machinery moving,
liquid bubbles]
[机械移动，
液体气泡]
[horn honks]
[喇叭鸣响]
Typical.
- You did it wrong, Squidward.
典型的。
- 你做错了，章鱼哥。
- I did it exactly
the way you did it!
- 我确实做到了
你就是这么做的！
- Everybody pipe down!
- 大家都安静下来！
I don't want to hear
another peep from anyone
我不想听
任何人的另一次窥视
until we get
to Food Con!
直到我们得到
去美食节！
- Peep.
- Not a peep!
- 窥视。
- 没有偷看！
- Peep!
- Not. A. Peep!
- 窥视！
- 不是。答：窥视！
- Peep!
- 窥视！
all: Peep's Cliff!
所有人：窥视悬崖！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[splashing]
[screaming]
[溅]
[尖叫]
[splashing]
[溅]
[yelling]
[大喊]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[crashing]
[崩溃]
[all sigh]
[众人叹息]
[clanging]
[叮叮当当]
[airbag deploys]
[安全气囊展开]
- [moans]
- Mr. Krabs?
- [呻吟]
- 蟹老板？
Blink if you're alive.
如果你还活着，请眨眼。
[moans]
[呻吟声]
- Oh, thank Neptune
we're all okay.
-哦，谢谢海王星
我们都很好。
- Well, at least we have
plenty of food
- 好吧，至少我们有
充足的食物
while we're
stuck out here.
当我们
被困在这里。
Ahh!
- [burps, moans]
啊！
- [打嗝，呻吟]
It was an accident!
这是一次意外！
They fell into my mouth.
[moans]
它们掉进了我的嘴里。
[呻吟声]
[all scream]
[所有人尖叫]
[panicked noises]
Don't worry, guys!
[惊慌的声音]
别担心，伙计们！
We can still win Food Con.
我们仍然可以赢得食品展。
There's one patty left.
还剩下一块肉饼。
- We gotta get moving,
the judging starts tomorrow!
- 我们得走了，
评审明天开始！
Now since you boys
caused the accident,
现在自从你们男孩们
导致事故发生，
you'll be
haulin' the trailer.
你会的
拖着拖车。
both: Yeah!
Hauling the trailer!
两人：是啊！
拖着拖车！
[wobbling, struggling]
[摇摇欲坠，挣扎]
[crashing]
[bubbles pop]
[崩溃]
[气泡破裂]
male narrator: And so,
SpongeBob and Patrick
男旁白：所以，
海绵宝宝和帕特里克
begin their harrowing task.
开始他们的艰巨任务。
Tethered to the wagon
not just by ropes,
拴在马车上
不只是通过绳索，
but by their own
foolish mistakes.
但由他们自己
愚蠢的错误。
Onward they trudge.
他们艰难前行。
[growling]
[咆哮]
Pushed by Mr. Krabs,
在蟹老板的推动下，
whose desires blind him
to the pain he inflicts.
谁的欲望蒙蔽了他
他所造成的痛苦。
In short, this whole trip
is beginning to look
总之这整个行程
正在开始寻找
like a whoopsie!
像百日咳一样！
- [wobbling, straining]
Ay.
- [摇晃，紧张]
哎呀。
Patrick, are you okay?
[yells, farts]
帕特里克，你还好吗？
[喊叫、放屁]
- 100%.
[stretching]
- 100%。
[伸展]
[pops]
Uh.
[流行音乐]
呃。
- Mr. Krabs, we've got to
stop for the night
- 蟹老板，我们必须这么做
停下来过夜
if you want Spongebob
and Patrick to live.
如果你想要海绵宝宝
和帕特里克一起生活。
I'm not saying
that's what I want,
我不是说
这就是我想要的，
I'm just telling you
the facts.
我只是告诉你
事实。
[bubbles pop]
[气泡破裂]
[spooky music]
[owl hoots]
[诡异的音乐]
[猫头鹰叫声]
[forest noises]
[森林噪音]
[shivering, whimpering]
[颤抖，呜咽]
[howling]
[startled noises]
[嚎叫]
[惊恐的声音]
- We must guard
this last patty
- 我们必须守护
最后这个小馅饼
with our very lives.
和我们的生命。
It's the only way
to win Food Con,
这是唯一的方法
赢得食品展，
and who knows what
scary, hungry things
谁知道是什么
可怕的、饥饿的东西
are out there in the woods,
waiting to gobble it up!
在树林里，
等着把它吞掉！
[growling]
[咆哮]
Positions, everyone.
大家各就各位。
[claws snapping, growling]
[爪子折断，咆哮]
[startled noises]
[growling]
[惊恐的声音]
[咆哮]
[all whimper]
[全都呜咽]
[meowing]
[喵喵叫]
- Aw, hey little fella.
- 噢，嘿小家伙。
[dramatic music]
[snarling]
[戏剧音乐]
[咆哮]
[growls]
[all scream]
[所有人尖叫]
[snarls]
[咆哮]
all: The patty!
全体：肉饼！
[panting]
- Oh, what are we gonna do!
[气喘吁吁]
- 哦，我们该怎么办！
- Don't eat my patty!
- 别吃我的肉饼！
[grunts] Yah!
- [screams]
[咕哝] 啊！
- [尖叫]
Whoa! [yells]
哇！ [喊叫]
[inhales, munches]
[吸气，咀嚼]
[spits, groans]
[吐口水，呻吟]
[screaming, thud]
- Oh!
[尖叫声、重击声]
- 哦！
- Squidward!
You saved the Krabby Patty!
- 章鱼哥！
你拯救了蟹黄饼！
- Whoopee.
[bubbles pop]
- 哎哟。
[气泡破裂]
[stomach rumbles]
[肚子咕咕叫]
[moans]
[呻吟声]
- Mm.
[door creaks]
- 毫米。
[门吱吱作响]
[fluttering]
[飘动]
[angelic glowing]
[天使般的光芒]
Maybe I could just
eat a pickle.
也许我可以
吃一个泡菜。
- Maybe I could just eat
the corner of the lettuce.
-也许我可以吃点东西
生菜的一角。
- I don't want to be a hog.
- 我不想成为一头猪。
I'll just eat
what's left over.
我就吃个饭
剩下什么。
- No!
We can't do that!
- 不！
我们不能那样做！
I know we're all hungry,
but we must stay focused.
我知道我们都饿了
但我们必须保持专注。
Remember Food Con!
Remember the cornucopia!
记住美食节！
记住聚宝盆！
- He says Food Con,
but all I hear is food.
- 他说食品展，
但我听到的都是食物。
[bubbles pop]
[气泡破裂]
[fire burns out]
[火熄灭了]
- Hey, SpongeBob,
you look tired.
- 嘿，海绵宝宝，
你看起来很累。
You want me to guard
the patty for a bit?
你要我守护
吃一点肉饼？
- [yawns] Thanks, Patrick.
That'd be great.
- [哈欠] 谢谢，帕特里克。
那太好了。
- [laughs]
- [snores]
- [笑]
- [打鼾]
[glass shattering]
[玻璃破碎]
- Ah--
- Patrick, no!
- 啊--
- 帕特里克，不！
- I can't believe
you thought I would eat it.
- 我不敢相信
你以为我会吃它。
- Patrick I'm sorry
I doubted you.
- 帕特里克，对不起
我怀疑你。
I'm just hungry and tired
and I feel like
我只是又饿又累
我觉得
I'm all alone
doing the right thing
我独自一人
做正确的事
and I want that-
[growling, slobbering]
我想要那个-
[咆哮，流口水]
Hey! Hey!
- But I'm hungry!
嘿！嘿！
- 但我饿了！
- Yah!
- Oh! [laughs]
- 啊！
- 哦！ [笑]
[bubbles pop]
[气泡破裂]
- I'll lull him to sleep
with a lovely lullaby.
- 我会哄他入睡
伴随着一首可爱的摇篮曲。
- Ooh, good idea.
- 哦，好主意。
Music soothes
the savage beast.
音乐舒缓
野蛮的野兽。
[plays clarinet]
What the!
[演奏单簧管]
什么啊！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- Did I say soothes?
I guess I meant enrages.
- 我有说安抚吗？
我想我的意思是愤怒。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[thud]
[babbles]
[砰]
[胡言乱语]
[honks, snaps]
[喇叭声、啪啪声]
- Everybody's a critic.
- 每个人都是批评家。
[bubbles pop]
[气泡破裂]
- Hey there, boyo.
- [screams]
- 嘿，小伙子。
- [尖叫]
- I've taken the liberty
of creating a safe
- 我已经冒昧了
创造一个安全的
to secure
our precious patty.
确保
我们珍贵的肉饼。
- Great idea, Mr. Krabs!
- 好主意，蟹老板！
- Just put it
right in here.
- 就放吧
就在这里。
I'll even step away
while you do it.
我什至会走开
当你这样做的时候。
Ahh.
啊。
- Pew, smells really bad
in there.
- 皮尤，气味很难闻
在那里。
- Okay, just do it already!
- [gasps]
- 好吧，就这么做吧！
- [喘气]
No!
- Enough of this.
不！
- 够了。
I am your boss,
我是你的老板，
and I order you
to give me that patty!
我命令你
把那个肉饼给我！
- No, Mr. Krabs,
I will not.
- 不，蟹老板先生，
我不会。
But I will give you these.
但我会给你这些。
[bell dings]
Nature patties!
[铃声]
天然肉饼！
- Oh, boy!
- Oh, delightful!
- 哦，孩子！
- 哦，令人愉快！
- Dig in, boys!
- 挖吧，孩子们！
[all munch]
[全部咀嚼]
[chewing, struggling]
[咀嚼，挣扎]
- Oh, it's like eating the
inside of a lawn mower.
- 哦，就像吃
割草机内部。
- I think mine
is mostly stones.
- 我想我的
大部分是石头。
- Out here we call them
forest tomatoes.
- 在这里我们称他们为
森林西红柿。
[both spit]
[两人都吐了]
[chews, moans]
[gulps]
[咀嚼，呻吟]
[吞咽]
- Enough of this!
- Mr. Krabs, remember Food Con!
- 够了！
- 蟹老板，记住美食节！
- You can't win Food Con
if you've starved to death!
- 你不可能赢得美食大赛
如果你已经饿死了！
Now, give me
that Krabby Patty, boyo.
现在，给我
那个蟹蟹帕蒂，男孩。
- No! I'm doing this
for your own good.
- 不！我正在做这个
为了你好。
I'm protecting you all
from yourselves!
我保护你们所有人
来自你们自己！
- Well, in that case,
you leave me no choice.
- 那么，在这种情况下，
你让我别无选择。
Get him!
抓住他！
[screams]
[all yelling]
[尖叫声]
[大家大喊]
[panicked noises]
[惊慌的声音]
- Whoa!
[grunts]
- 哇！
[咕哝]
[yelling]
[大喊]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[stomach rumbles]
[肚子咕咕叫]
- Hey, psst.
It's me, the Patty.
- 嘿，嘘。
是我，帕蒂。
- Oh, hi.
- 哦，嗨。
- It's just me and you
out here now.
- 只有我和你
现在就在这儿。
So, just do it.
Eat me.
所以，就这么做吧。
吃我吧
- What about Food Con?
- 食品展怎么样？
- Oh, forget Food Con.
- 哦，忘了美食节吧。
You're starving,
and I'm right here.
你快饿死了，
我就在这里。
[slurps]
- Maybe you're right.
[啜饮]
- 也许你是对的。
- Of course I'm right,
I'm a talking sandwich.
- 我当然是对的
我是一个会说话的三明治。
- Yes, a sandwich has
no reason to lie.
- 是的，三明治有
没有理由撒谎。
Ahh.
[dramatic music]
啊。
[戏剧音乐]
[gasps] No!
I made a vow.
[喘气]不！
我发誓。
I will not eat you.
我不会吃你的。
- Shh, shh, I can hear him
over there.
- 嘘，嘘，我能听到他的声音
在那儿。
He's arguing
with the patty.
他在争论
和肉饼。
Let's get him! [grunts]
- [moans]
我们来抓住他吧！ [咕哝]
- [呻吟]
[grunting, thud]
[咕噜声，重击声]
- Oh!
[thud, farts]
- 哦！
[咚咚，放屁]
- [hums]
- Don't let him get away!
- [哼哼]
- 别让他跑了！
- Hungry!
- 饥饿的！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[yells, whimpers]
[喊叫，呜咽]
Food Con!
食品骗局！
[crowd chattering]
[人群议论]
- I'm filled with meat.
I love being filled with meat.
- 我已经吃饱了
我喜欢充满肉的感觉。
- Ahh
- Get him!
- 啊啊
- 抓住他！
- Guys, we're here!
- 伙计们，我们来了！
- Hungry, hungry, hungry!
- 饿了，饿了，饿了！
- You don't have to
eat the patty.
- 你不必
吃肉饼。
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
[thudding]
- And I hereby award
[重击]
- 我特此授予
the golden
cornucopia to--
金色的
聚宝盆到——
[straining, yells]
[用力，大喊]
- Please, try a delicious
Krabby Patty!
- 请尝尝美味
蟹蟹帕蒂！
- What's this?
A late entry?
- 这是什么？
迟到了？
Hmm.
唔。
[bell dings]
[铃声]
- [in slow motion]
Nature patty!
- [慢动作]
自然肉饼！
- [slow-motion]
Mmm, Krabby Patty.
- [慢动作]
嗯，克拉比帕蒂。
Ahh, um!
[chews]
啊，嗯！
[咀嚼]
[whimpers, gasps]
[呜咽，喘息]
[munches, chewing]
[咀嚼，咀嚼]
- Mmm, this is
the most complex,
- 嗯，这是
最复杂的，
mmm, organic,
mmm, irresistible flavor
嗯，有机的，
嗯嗯，难以抗拒的味道
I have ever had
the pleasure of tasting!
我曾经有过
品尝的乐趣！
[munches]
- Ohh--
[咀嚼]
- 噢--
The winner is...
获胜者是...
Mmm, the Krabby Patty!
嗯，蟹肉饼！
- Oh, excuse me, sir,
that's not the real Krabby--
- 哦，对不起，先生，
那不是真正的蟹蟹——
- Quit your truthing, boy.
- 别说实话了，孩子。
We won.
[cheers and applause]
我们赢了。
[欢呼和掌声]
- The Krabby Patty won!
It won!
- 蟹黄饼赢了！
它赢了！
- Yes.
[munches]
- 是的。
[咀嚼]
[machinery moving,
horn honks]
[机械移动，
喇叭鸣响]
Oh.
哦。